[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community
In the lectures, Emily talked about nearest neighbor models and
在前面的课程当中 Emily已经讨论过了最近邻居模型以及
how they can be used for document retrieval.
怎样把这个模型运用到文章检索上
So today, we're gonna actually do some cool document retrievals
所以现在我们要真正地动手做一些很酷的文章检索
using simple nearest neighbor models.
运用简单的最近邻居模型
Next we're going to build
接着我们将要构建
a nearest neighbor model for document retrieval.
一个用于文章检索的最近邻居模型
And here we go, nearest neighbor model for
让我们开始吧 用于文章提取的最近邻居模型
Again, you could implement your own, but we have one already implemented
同样的 你可以实现你自己的模型 但是我们有一个已经实现的版本
here that you can use, which is great for this first course.
在这里你可以直接使用 对于这第一门课来说很棒
We're gonna use the one from the offline, and it is called nearest_neighbors.
我们将要使用的是一个叫做nearest_neighbors的离线模型
And just like that use the verb create to create a nearest neighbor model.
像之前一样 使用单词create来创建一个最近邻居模型
So we're gonna give it this input.
我们会给这个模型一个输入
The people table.
也就是人物的表格
And we have to say what features we're gonna use in the nearest neighbors.
然后我们需要指定 在最近邻居模型中 我们将使用哪些特征
So the features are gonna be the tfidf, tfidf.
所以我们将会使用tfidf来作为特征
Just like we've been using for the cosine distances above.
就像我们之前所使用的余弦相似性
And I'm going to provide a label column and
然后我们提供一个标签列给模型
this label column is going to be the name.
这个标签列就是人物的名字
So when I return my nearest neighbors, it's going to
所以当我们的最近邻居模型返回值的时候 它将会
return the actual label of the nearest neighbor, so the name of the person.
返回最近邻居的真实标签 也是就是那个人的名字
And that will make the print out prettier.
并且那样会使输出结果更加整洁美观
So that's cool that it's there for us.
所以这很酷 这个模型就在这里可以被我们使用了
So it should only take a few seconds.
这个训练过程会持续几秒钟
And we will have, now there we are.
我们最终会得到它的 好 现在我们已经得到了训练好的模型
We will have a nearest neighbor model for document retrieval.
我们已经有了一个能用于文章检索的最近邻居模型了
So now we can use it, so let's go ahead and use it.
所以现在我们可以使用它了 让我们继续并运用这个模型吧
So I'm going to just create another header here and
所以在这里我会创建另一个标题
say applying the nearest-neighbors model for
并且写上应用最近邻居模型到
retrieval, and let's see what we get.
检索上 然后我们一起来看看我们会得到什么结果
So the first question is, so let's do our first query.
所以第一个问题是 就让我们做第一次的查询
So who is closest to Obama?
谁和奥巴马 的距离最近？
So who are the closest people to Obama in the data set.
也是就在数据集中 哪一个人是和奥巴马距离最近的人？
So if you just take our neighbor model,
所以如果你使用我们的邻居模型
we can use the method query, the function query associated with it,
我们可以使用query方法 也就是模型带有的一个名为query的函数
which just queries the model with some input.
这个函数使用一些输入来查询整个模型
So in this case Obama as our input, and gives me back the nearest-neighbor.
在这个例子中 奥巴马就是我们的输入 然后函数会返回给我们最近的邻居
So where the nearest-neighbor is to Obama, we'll compute it, and it's very quick.
所以谁是奥巴马 的最近邻居呢？ 我们会计算这个结果 并且非常快
And I say, okay, the closest person to Obama is Obama himself, which makes sense.
然后我们可以看到 和奥巴马 最近的人是奥巴马 本身 这很合理
But after that, we have Joe Biden, who is the current US vice president.
但在那之后 我们会看到 乔·拜登 也就是现任的美国副总统
So the president is closest to the vice president.
所以总统和副总统的距离是最近的
And then we find a few other politicians, including former president Bill Clinton,
然后我们会看到另外一些政治家 包括前任总统 比尔·克林顿
which we saw above.
这就是我们所看到的
[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community